paramountcommunication.com 2011-12-01

# Paramount Communication Group

This statement is effective as of 10/20/10. For the most current version of the Paramount Communication Group, Inc. Privacy Statement, please visit www.ParamountCommunication.com

## Overview

At Paramount, we respect the privacy needs of our valued customers and members. This Privacy Policy outlines what specific information is gathered by Paramount and how that information is used.

Paramount works to ensure the highest degree of protection for consumers and businesses. We will continue to work to comply with strict standards for online privacy, security, business practices, transaction integrity and availability. If you have any specific questions about the Paramount Privacy Statement, please contact us via email at [privacy@ParamountCommunication.com](mailto:privacy@ParamountCommunication.com).

## Collection and Use of Information by Paramount

Your personal information is used to create your personal access to products on the site, and to contact you in the course of using the products.  Your personal information may also be transferred to us from another Company in order to send you emails that you have requested.  Financial information that is collected is used to verify your identity, to pay for a product or service, or to bill either you or your company for products and services, as applicable. Demographic and profile data collected by Paramount is used to optimize our Website or any requested email communications, and to display information that is more relevant to you.

Your email address is used to send you information that you have requested. As part of your use of any Paramount product, Paramount allows you to elect to receive, or not receive, certain information from Paramount. Paramount adheres strictly to permission-based email policy. Paramount will not send you unsolicited email information, commercial offers or advertisements. All emails that you have requested, other than transactional emails, will include an option to unsubscribe. Unsubscribe requests are fulfilled promptly and no further communications will be sent to users who have stated that they do not wish to receive the specified information.

## Cookies and Web Beacons 

### Cookies.

A “cookie” is a small text file that is transferred to your computer by our Web server.  We may use two types of cookies—“session cookies” and “persistent cookies.”

### Session Cookies.

A “session cookie” is a temporary cookie that expires when you close your browser.  A session cookie assigns a randomly-generated, unique identification number to your computer when you access our Site or open our email.  Assigning your computer a number facilitates the proper functioning of the features of our Web site and email, by permitting us to maintain a persistent “state” for your session.  We also use session cookies to collect information about the ways visitors use this Web site or an email – which pages are visited, which links are used, and how long a user stays on each page.  We analyze this information (known as “clickstream information”) to better understand our visitors’ interests and needs and to improve the content and functionality of this Web site and our emails.

### Persistent Cookies.

When you visit this Web site, or open an email from us,  we may place one or more “persistent cookies” on your computer.  Unlike a “session cookie,” a persistent cookie does not expire when you close your browser.  It stays on your computer until it expires (for example, at the end of the calendar year) or until you delete it.

Some persistent cookies simply “tag” your computer so that the next time you visit (or someone using your computer visits), our server will recognize you, not by name, but by the “tag” on your computer.  This will enable us to provide you with a personalized experience even if we do not know who you are.  It will also allow us to collect more accurate information about the ways people use this Web site, and our emails, for example, how people use this Web site on their first visit and how often they return.  If, at some point, you create a user identity, we may link the information collected by these persistent cookies to information in our database that identifies you personally.  We may also transfer this information to a cookie and place it on your computer’s hard drive so that our web server can read this information each time you visit this Web site or click on an email.  In either case, using persistent cookies permits us to provide you with a more personalized experience and, in some cases, may save you the trouble of re-entering information already in our database.

If you do not wish to receive cookies, you may set your browser to reject cookies or to alert you when a cookie is placed on your computer.  You may also delete our cookies as soon as you leave our Web site.  Although you are not required to accept our cookies, if you set your browser to reject cookies, you will not be able to use all of the features and functionality of this Web site.  For example, you will not be able to purchase products and services on this Web site.

### Web Beacons.

Web beacons (also referred to as “tracking pixels” or “action tags”) are graphic images, usually no larger than 1 pixel x 1 pixel, placed at various locations on our Site and in our emails.  Web beacons help us recognize the cookies on your browser.  Like cookies, Web beacons help us collect information about the ways visitors use our Site.  They also help us identify browser types, IP addresses, search terms that bring visitors to our Site, and the domain names of the Web sites that refer traffic to us.  The information collected by Web beacons does not identify you personally.  However, if you have created a user identity on one of your visits to this Web site, for example, by making a purchase, we may link the information we collect using Web beacons to the information that identifies you personally and use it in the same ways as we use the information we collect using cookies.  Lastly, we utilize web beacons to provide us with more information on any emails we send out, in particular, the web beacons will send us information to let us know that you have received and opened any e-mail you have chosen to receive from us. 

## Information Use by Third Parties

### Our Partners.

Paramount Communication Group is an online service provider. We pass on to our Partner the privacy preferences you have expressed from an email you have responded to. For example, if you have asked to be added to our Partner’s mailing lists, we will pass on that information.  If you have declined an opportunity to be added to our Partner’s mailing lists, we will also pass on that information.

### Our Service Providers.

Paramount Communication Group employs other companies, including our affiliates, to provide services to us or on our behalf.  For example, we may use other companies to maintain this Web site, to process payments, detect and prevent fraud, deliver packages, send mail or email, provide customer service, or analyze various clickstream data and consumer behavior.  These companies are required by contract to use the personal information we share with them only to perform services to us or on our behalf and to protect the confidentiality of your personal information.

### As Disclosed in a Privacy Notice.

We may share specific personal information as disclosed in a specific Privacy Notice posted on the page or area of this Web site where you provided that information.

### To Comply With Legal Requirements, Cooperate With Law Enforcement, Prevent Fraud and Other Crimes, and Protect Legal Rights, Property, You and Others.

There are other limited circumstances in which we may share the personal information in our databases with unrelated third parties.  For example, we may disclose the personal information we collect on this Site or in an email without notifying you when we, in good faith, believe disclosure is appropriate to comply with the law or a regulatory requirement; to comply with a subpoena or court order; to cooperate with law enforcement or other governmental investigations (without necessarily requiring the law enforcement or government agency requesting the information to formally serve us with a subpoena); to prevent or investigate a possible crime, such as fraud or identity theft; to enforce a contract; to protect the legal rights, property or safety of Paramount our affiliates, our employees, agents, other users or the public in general or to protect your vital interests.  We also reserve the right to report to appropriate law enforcement or government agencies any activities that we, in good faith, believe to be unlawful without providing notice to you.

### In Connection With Corporate Events.

We may transfer your personal information to another company (either an affiliate of Paramount or an unrelated third party) that has acquired the stock or assets of Paramount Communication Group, one of our affiliates, or one of our operating divisions, for example, as the result of a sale, merger, reorganization, insolvency, dissolution or liquidation.  If such a transfer occurs, the acquiring company’s use of your personal information will still be subject to this Privacy Policy, any applicable Privacy Notices, and the privacy preferences you have expressed to us Contact Lists, Campaign Content and Campaign Reports. 

Paramount ensures that all contact lists, email content and reports remain private and confidential. Any use of Paramount systems must be in compliance with our Acceptable Use Policy - to protect against inappropriate use (illegal, abusive, obscene, threatening, etc.). 

**Paramount Communication Group will not sell, rent, loan or allow external access to a customer’s contact lists.** Nor will Paramount themselves use customer’s contact lists for any purpose other than those agreed to in writing. 

## How Can You Access and Correct Your Personal Information?

We strive to maintain the accuracy and integrity of the personal information in our databases and to keep that information up-to-date.  We provide ways for you to access your personal information as required by applicable law, so that you can correct inaccuracies or update your personal information.  We generally do not charge for this service, however, we reserve the right to charge a fee as permitted by applicable law.

If you would like to review, correct or challenge your personal information, please contact us by e-mail at [privacy@ParamountCommunication.com](mailto:privacy@ParamountCommunication.com). 

We will respond to reasonable requests within the time limits established by applicable law or within a reasonable time if no time limit is established by applicable law.  For your protection, we may ask you for additional information to verify your identity.  In most cases, we will provide the access you request and correct or delete any inaccurate personal information you discover.  We reserve the right, however, to limit or deny your request to the extent permitted by applicable law if: 1) the disclosure may harm the life, the body, the property and the rights of third parties, 2) the disclosure may lead to a breach of applicable law and regulation, or 3) where you have failed to provide sufficient evidence to verify your identity.

## This Privacy Policy May Change

We reserve the right to update or modify this Privacy Policy, at any time and without prior notice, by posting the revised version of this Privacy Policy on this Web site.  These changes will only apply to personal information we collect after we have posted the revised Privacy Policy.  Your use of this Web site or an email following any such change constitutes your agreement that all personal information collected from or about you through this Web site or email after the revised Privacy Policy is posted will be subject to the terms of the revised Privacy Policy.

To alert you to these changes, we will update the effective date of this Privacy Policy.  We will also provide a notice at the top of this Privacy Policy for at least 30 days after the new effective date and highlight the changes so that you can locate them easily.  Unless the change is a minor change (such as a change in our contact information) or a non-substantive change (such as the reformatting of our Privacy Policy), we will post notices on the page where you submit your order and/or on other relevant pages of this Web site for 30 days after the new effective date to alert you to the change. 

## Children’s Privacy

Our Web site and emails are not directed at nor targeted to children.  No one who has not reached the age of majority in his or her country may use this Web site unless supervised by an adult.

We do not use our Web site to knowingly solicit personal information from or market to anyone under the age of majority in his or her country.  Our goal is to comply with applicable laws and regulations relating to collection and use of information from children, including the Children’s On-line Privacy Protection Act of the United States and other applicable laws or regulations.  If you believe that we have received information from a child or other person protected under such laws, please notify us immediately by email at [privacy@ParamountCommunication.com](mailto:privacy@ParamountCommunication.com) and we will take reasonable steps to remove that information from our databases. 

## Information Exchanges and Transactions

Privacy, anti-hacking and other security technology has been implemented throughout our application system. Information exchanges and transactions, passwords, contact lists (uploading and storing online) and billing related data between you and our application system are protected using various technologies (multiple PIX firewalls, etc.). This ensures a very high degree of security. 

## Credit Card Information 

Paramount allows you to purchase email marketing services in a variety of ways. When credit card billing is chosen, information is transferred using industry-leading, secure transmission technology including SSL and HTTPS (the transmission standard used for transactions by major financial institutions). The information is then encrypted using Data Encryption and stored securely so that it is ready to handle your transactions.

## Governing Law 

This Privacy Policy and our Privacy Notices are governed by the laws of the State of Minnesota, United States of America, without regard to its conflict of law principles. 

## The Bottom Line

Maintaining the privacy of your information is of paramount importance to us as it helps foster confidence, goodwill and stronger relationships with you, our customers. If, at any time, you have questions or concerns about our privacy practices, please feel free contact us at [privacy@ParamountCommunication.com](mailto:privacy@ParamountCommunication.com).
